SILAS JIMMY

Nairobi, Kenya | +254 719 773 594 | <u>iimmysilas17@gmail.com</u> | <u>LinkedIn</u> | <u>Github</u>

SUMMARY

I am a software engineer who has been in the tech industry for three years now. My skills are versatile across the software development process and implementing fullstack applications. I develop user interfaces, design back-end architectures and enable a seamless communication between the front-end and back-end. I am a smart worker with a knack for finding solutions to problems as well as learning and using new technologies to boost user experience.

SKILLS

Front-end development: HTML, CSS, Back-end development: Python, Nodejs,

JavaScript, Sass, Vuejs, Ionic, Figma, Canva, Flask, SQL, NoSQL

Material design

APIs: REST, WebSockets Tools: VSCode, Github

Cloud Services: AWS, Firebase

EDUCATION

Udacity Nanodegree, Cloud Developer
Remote/Online May 2022 - June 2022

Coursework: Cloud fundamentals, Fullstack applications, AWS, CI/CD tools, Monoliths and

Microservices, Serverless applications

UdacityNanodegree, Python ProgrammingRemote/OnlineJanuary 2022 - April 2022

Coursework: Basic and intermediate Python concepts, Functional programming, OOP, Web programs, Testing, Documentation, Software development best practices

Pwani University Bachelor of Science, Computer Science
Kilifi, Kenya September 2017 - December 2021

Coursework: Programming, Web development, Networking, Database management

EXPERIENCE

Cyeco Africa Limited Kilifi, Kenya
Chief Marketing Officer March 2023 - Present

Description

Organise and oversee marketing strategies aiming to shape the company's brand and promote the company's products and services.

Responsibilities and Achievements

- Maintaining and promoting the company's brand identity by defining brand values and ensuring consistency across all marketing channels attracting 50 customers in a week.
- Organise marketing strategies by identifying potential customers, designing creative targeted ads and ensuring alignment with the company's objectives.
- Designing and implementing the company's website as well as creating user interfaces of the company's mobile application improving interaction by 20%.
- Interacting with the customers to understand their needs and interacting with data analytics to assess marketing effectiveness and make informed decisions.

January 2022 - April 2022

Description

* Research project to find a tech solution that promotes good health and well being by implementing a web-based meal planning system.

Responsibilities and Achievements

- Continuous improvement of the system by implementing the RAD software model which increased user feedback by 50% and lower development time by 30%.
- Designing of a simple and appealing user interface as well as a seamless user experience that elevated user engagement by 20%.
- Raise immense awareness about local foods and the importance of healthy eating habits among users.
- Reduce meal planning time by 65% using a decisive algorithm to generate balanced diet meals.

PROJECTS

Trivia API May 2021 - June 2021

❖ A RESTful web application made to hold trivial subjects and play word games. Responsible for implementing API's endpoints, write test cases and design error-handling mechanisms for erroneous requests.

Technology: Python, React, Flask, Postgres

Link to project

Dema Planner

January 2022 - April 2022

❖ A web-based meal planning system used to generate balanced diets from locally available foods and connect users to nearest eateries. Responsible for implementing the user interfaces and designing the back-end architecture using firebase. Improved data retrieval by 26% using NoSQL database and shortened planning time by 65%.

Technology: Sass, Vuejs, Firebase

Link to project

Udagram

June 2021 - July 2021

❖ A cloud application that allows users to register and log in to a web client, post pictures and process them through an image filtering system. Responsible for refactoring the monolith app to microservices which decreased complexity by 20% and incremented development and deployment speed by 35% using automated CI/CD tools.

Technology: Angular, Ionic, TypeScript,

Link to project

Sass, Node-Express, AWS

INTERESTS

Programming, Problem solving, Data analysis, Machine learning, Research, Continuous learning

LANGUAGES

English, Swahili